Oleg Trafimovich

Lead Data Scientist

Amsterdam, the Netherlands +31 616308146 oleg.trafimovich@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/oleg-t English, Russian

- 4.5 years of experience as a Senior and Lead Data Scientist.
- 3 years as a Lead Software Architect with data analytics usage for development-related decisions.
- 14+ years of overall experience in IT (Software Engineer, Software Architect, Data Scientist), mostly in Senior or Team Lead roles.

Performing EDAs, hypothesis testing, modelling on large proprietary datasets in order to better understand and predict the technical infrastructure stability and product usage, identify the product issues and customers priorities. Using statistical methods, machine learning models and custom data visualisations.

Preparing reports and presenting data analysis findings to the product stakeholders and development team representatives. Identifying and communicating key insights that help to make new decisions regarding the product development and customer communication as well as new directions for analysis and research.

Designing technical specifications that are used for building new data pipelines and visualisation dashboards. Leading and mentoring other team members.

Technologies - current and recently used

Pandas, Dask

PySpark

Scipy

SQL

Hadoop, HDFS

Big data formats

(Parquet, Avro)
 ElasticSearch

Scikit-learn

Tensorflow

Pytorch

Keras

Xgboost

NLTKMatplotlib

Seaborn

D3.js

Grafana

Tableau

Working Experience

Lead Data Scientist	Liberty Global / Epam Working as on-site contractor	Since Jan 2018, 4.5 years
Lead Software Architect	Liberty Global / Epam Working as on-site contractor	Feb 2015 - Jan 2018, 3 years
Senior and Lead Software Developer (C++, Java)	HTC, Viber	2008-2015, 7 years

Education and certifications



Udacity

Nanodegree, Natural Language Processing

Feb 2019 – May 2019



Software Engineering Institute

Documenting Software Architectures Software Architecture Principles and Practices

Nov 2018 - Oct 2018



Udacity

Nanodegree, Deep Learning Foundation

Feb 2017 – May 2017

SCALED AGILE

Scaled Agile

SAFe Agilist, License 74977743-3838

Jul 2016



Coursera

The Data Scientist's Toolbox, License 9CKJ4NNVDZ	Nov 2015
R Programming, RAH6VBTGR5	Nov 2015
Managing Project Risks and Changes, XNRCBUPE3CAM	Oct 2015
Budgeting and Scheduling Projects, P2FWHWWZR8FM	Sep 2015
Initiating and Planning Projects, 4375J5D7ZTT5	Jul 2015



Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

2004 - 2009

Artificial Intelligence

Hobbies and interests

<u>Photography</u>, cyberpunk, biology. Artificial Intelligence has been my passion since high school. Favorite books: A Thousand Brains (Jeff Hawkins), Society of Mind (Marvin Minsky), New Kind of Science (Stephen Wolfram), The Extended Phenotype (Richard Dawkins), Signals and Boundaries (John H. Holland)